<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Connected Displays</title>
    <link>http://www.connected-displays.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Connected Displays</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.connected-displays.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New Tutorial: Umbrella Reminder with Particle Photon Webhooks</title>
      <link>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/photon-rain-led-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/photon-rain-led-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.connected-displays.com/post/photon-rain-led-tutorial/banner.png&#34;/&gt;
        
        I live in NYC and the weather can change suddenly. It may look nice outside my window when I&amp;rsquo;m getting ready to leave, but a storm could be inbound. I&amp;rsquo;d like to have something that tells me to &amp;ldquo;bring your umbrella&amp;rdquo; right next to the door. This is my first project done with the Particle Photon, and because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a comprehensive tutorial on this type of project, I wrote it up in tutorial form.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Button Review</title>
      <link>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/internet-button-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/internet-button-review/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.connected-displays.com/post/internet-button-review/banner.png&#34;/&gt;
        
        The Internet Button is a product by Particle that combines their Photon WiFi dev board with a well designed adapter board containing several inputs (4x buttons and an accelerometer) and outputs (11 LEDs and a buzzer). It&amp;rsquo;s intended to be a good starting point for using the Photon, requiring no soldering to use. The 11 LEDs arranged in a ring and buzzer make it a good platform for a connected display project.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESP8266 Weather Display</title>
      <link>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/esp8266-weather-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/esp8266-weather-display/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.connected-displays.com/post/esp8266-weather-display/banner.jpg&#34;/&gt;
        
        I came across a tutorial in the Adafruit Learning System about a WiFi-connected Weather Display that caught my eye. The tutorial shows how to use Huzzah - Adafruit’s breakout for the ESP8266 WiFi module - to display weather data on an OLED screen. The project is listed as an intermediate level project, because it requires a PHP script to be running on a separate computer or Raspberry Pi to translate data from a weather forecast API to a format the microcontroller can handle.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Stickers Product Preview</title>
      <link>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/smart-stickers-product-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/smart-stickers-product-preview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.connected-displays.com/post/smart-stickers-product-preview/banner.jpg&#34;/&gt;
        
        &lt;p&gt;There’s an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/smart-sticker-customizable-real-time-display#/story&#34;&gt;Indiegogo campaign&lt;/a&gt; running for Smart Stickers - low cost bluetooth connected E-ink displays.  The product looks interesting, and I want this to become a real product, but I have some serious doubts about the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MoodLight Product Preview</title>
      <link>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/moodlight-product-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 12:22:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/moodlight-product-preview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.connected-displays.com/post/moodlight-product-preview/banner.jpg&#34;/&gt;
        
        Connor Nishijima created an online service that monitors Twitter for people expressing their emotions, and is in the middle of a Kickstarter campaign to show that data on a WiFi connected display. The twitter data is analyzed by a server, and you can see it working on the MoodLighting Stats page. The display polls the server for new data every second, and lights up nine LEDs to display the current state of emotions.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lametric Time - Initial Review</title>
      <link>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/lametric-time-initial-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/lametric-time-initial-review/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.connected-displays.com/post/lametric-time-initial-review/banner.png&#34;/&gt;
        
        I was excited to learn about the LaMetric Time when it launched on Kickstarter in July 2014. I was lucky enough to be an early backer at the $119 price for a plug-in LaMetric (no battery), and I just opened it up and spent about an hour playing with it. LaMetric Time was interesting to me because of its pixelated LED display and potential for customization, displaying any data that&amp;rsquo;s available from the web.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raincheck Product Preview</title>
      <link>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/raincheck-product-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.connected-displays.com/post/raincheck-product-preview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.connected-displays.com/post/raincheck-product-preview/banner.jpg&#34;/&gt;
        
        Raincheck is an umbrella stand that knows if it&amp;rsquo;s going to rain. It has a WiFi connected LED display to show you the chance of precipitation in the next eight hours, built into a beautiful hand-crafted umbrella stand. I had just finished my first Particle Photon project - an indicator to tell if it’s going to rain in the next four hours - when I saw Raincheck in my twitter feed.
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
